Finding Aid for Cecil J. McHale papers, 1927-1948
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Cecil J. McHale papers 1927-1948
McHale, Cecil John, 1899-1948.
1 linear foot.
85297 Aa 2
Professor of library science at the University of Michigan; organizational files, correspondence, articles, and teaching materials.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was transferred from the University of Michigan School of Library Science (donor no. 4855 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Cecil John McHale was a professor of library science at the University of Michigan.
The Cecil McHale papers relate to his professional activities, especially with the American Library Association, the Association of American Library Schools, and the Michigan Library Association. Also included are course materials, articles, reviews, and bibliographies.
Subjects:
American Library Association.; Association of American Library Schools.; Libraries--United States.; Michigan Library Association.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan. School of Library Science.
- Biographical
  - Miscellaneous material (Box 1)
- General correspondence
  - 1938-1948, 11 folders (Box 1)
- Professional files
  - American Library Association
    - Council, 1942-1947 (Box 1)
    - Library Administration Committee, 1941-1946 (Box 1)
    - Statistics committee, 1941-1946 (Box 1)
  - Association of American Library Schools
    - 1941-1943 (Box 1)
    - 1944-1947 (Box 1)
    - 1948 (Box 1)
  - Michigan Library Association
    - General, 1935-1942 and 1946 (Box 1)
    - Planning Committee, 1939-1941 (Box 1)
  - Conference of Librarians of Large Public Libraries, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Library reports (Box 1)
- Articles, Reviews, Bibliographies, etc.
  - By date
    - Undated and 1927-1929 (Box 1)
    - 1932-1935 (Box 1)
    - 1939-1940 for Michigan Librarian "Highlights" (Box 1)
    - 1940-1945 (Box 1)
    - 1946-1948 (Box 1)
  - Published articles and reprints (Box 1)
  - Speeches (Box 1)
- Teaching
  - Teaching Service Records (Box 1)
  - Course materials
    - Book selection (Box 1)
    - Library Administration (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous courses (Box 1)
- Other Materials
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Survey files
    - General (Box 1)
    - Lansing (Box 1)
    - Monroe (Box 1)
  - Letters with and about former students, 1939-1948 (Box 1)